entitledto.co.uk 2018-09-02

# Privacy Matters. Our Policies. | entitledto

At entitledto we do not capture or store any personal information about individuals who use this website, except where you voluntarily choose to give us your personal details via email, or by using an electronic form, or enquiring about any of our services.

Like most sites, we do use Google Analytics, to help us understand visitor behaviour and improve the website, but this is information that is collected and presented anonymously. 

We will not link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user. In fact, we will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifiable information from any source, unless you explicitly submit that information via a fill-in form.

**Anonymity**

All this means that your visit to our site is  _anonymous_. Note the deliberate emphasis on anonymous, as no personally identifiable information is collected about you unless you explicitly submit that information via a fill-in form on this website. So if we need personal info from you - for example your email address to provide you with benefit updates - we will ask for it and you will have the option to provide it or not.

In compliance with the EU Directive on Privacy and Electronic Communications, any personal data you provide to entitledto will be used exclusively for providing you with the information you have requested.

**When personal information is submitted**

If you have registered for benefit updates via email we request your name and email address and potentially other non-specific demographic information. For example, your gender and location. We do this firstly to ensure you are not a robot or spammer, and secondly because the more information we have the better we can understand what content is of interest to readers. If you want to have your details removed from our records you can achieve this by clicking on the “unsubscribe” button that appears at the bottom of our mail outs.

**Postcodes**

We ask users to provide their postcode when they fill in the Benefit Calculator. We ask for that information  _exclusively_  to determine which Local Authority area you live in, so that we can determine your entitlement to Council Tax Support and other benefits where location is important. Where policies are set by Local Authorities, or are rolled out in different areas at different times, we need your post code in order to give you an accurate benefits estimate. However, we don’t store your postcode, so once you’ve completed your calculation and left our site, that information is no longer held in our system. We also give you the option to select your Local Authority from our A-Z menu in place of entering a postcode.

**3rd Party Tracking**  

We don’t really like tracking of any kind. That said, we do use social "love" buttons. If you click on a social love button, most will set a third-party cookie e.g. Twitter, Google +1, etc. Unfortunately, there is no way around this if you wish to share content socially - social networks use 3rd-party cookies.

As mentioned, we also use Google Analytics to understand, in aggregate, how visitors use the site and to allow us to improve it. This also involves the use of a small cookie, in exactly the same way as most sites in the internet.

If this concerns you, you can always block 3rd-party cookies. The social buttons will still work, but no visitor data will be sent to them. 

**Changes**

We do envisage creating new services that can provide tailored support for our users, but when we do, we will let you know about those changes to the extent that they alter this Privacy Policy.

**To summarise**

For many people, the ability to complete the Benefits Calculation in a safe, anonymous way is a vital part of using entitledto. We respect that and do our utmost to design our systems in a way that respects and preserves your anonymity.
